then we built it and we now it has
10,000 employees we we have a building
in uh Manhattan 12 story building and
and uh we only
used uh the principles of mental seeds
and it means uh plant a seed for the
thing you want to see in your future and
then it will come to you because much of
the world that you see around you is
perceptions it's much of it is
perceptions so um and planting a seed as
we said last night there are four steps
to planting a seed uh I'll review those
four and then we'll go on to something
new okay so you can plant a seed i' I've
gone to many many countries tens of
thousands of people we're very popular
in China Russia South America Singapore
everywhere uh not Australia yet uh
but I listen to people I see what do
they want in their lives and I'll tell
you there are three immediate things
that people want first one is we said
last night Financial Independence I want
to be financially independent you know
you would be interested I think to
know that all over the world when you
ask people what is their dream they will
say Financial
Independence and not wealth they don't
say wealth they say I want to be
financially independent and then you say
why and they say because I want to do
other things with my life I don't want
to struggle my whole life for money I
want to make enough money to help other
people and I after many years of
teaching 30 35 years of teaching you
should know all over the world people's
dream is to help other people okay you
think not but it is all these people are
like I want to become independent
financially because I want to make
donations and I want to support this and
I want to to see children have good
education and I want to help poor people
and all over the world it's the same in
every country that I've been to uh many
many countries that's the first basic
goal of people second goal is
companionship uh relationships it's
lonely to come home to a big uh house
you know the more rooms the more lonely
you know and then you're sitting in one
in the corner of one of the rooms eating
dinner by yourself and no one to talk to
no one to tell about what you did today
the little successes in your life and
the the problems in your life we need
companionship everybody would like to
have a companion uh someone to share
their life with so I was in South China
one day guango somebody asked me or
Shenzhen I don't know somebody asked me
the question you know can you use this
method uh not just to make a big company
but could you actually plant a partner
could you plant a future partner so I
was like oh they didn't teach us that in
the monastery but uh I thought about it
and then we dug up some scriptures and
yeah you can you can use it to create a
partner and then somebody else of course
wanted to know if they could just make
some small improvements on their
partner uh with uh mental seeds and uh
you can you can so you don't have to be
in your life without a partner if you
understand this system you you don't
have to be in your life without a
partner and you also don't have to spend
your life with someone who can't figure
out to lower the toilet
seat uh after 20 years of training you
know so uh you can change anything about
your partner everything without talking
to them okay because they are they are
basically coming from you you can change
anything you can you can improve your
partner you can make them perfect if you
understand these principles that we will
talk about tonight
okay then other people say no I have a
nice partner I I have a nice house I
have a nice income but I have physical
pains I have a cancer or I have a bad
back or you know or I have lost my
youthful energy and it kills me or or My
creativity that I had when I was young
and it kills me you know if you've been
a very creative person or you've been a
person who who was juggling businesses
at the same time and then suddenly you
can't do it anymore or you can't think
of the next new idea it's very very
frustrating or you're musician or an
actor and you lose your touch uh it's
very very frustrating and uh you lose
your youth you lose your the sharpness
and Clarity of of a youthful mind and
and the body of a youth and then it's
very frustrating for a person uh to say
I used to do that yoga post like 5 years
ago could do that most you know and then
that's very frustrating or or you start
telling people about what a creative guy
you were 10 years ago because you
haven't created anything new and can you
fix that you see uh when you say that
things are coming from seeds in your
mind does it apply to the Mind itself is
the condition of your mind and your own
energy also coming from seeds in your
own mind and we say yes it's it's
something something therefore it's
coming from seeds in your mind
everything is coming from seeds in your
mind then people are you know many
people will jump on me and say uh
metaphorically and say uh can you can
you plant peace in your mind you know
can you plant a peaceful mind and yeah
you can plant it you can use the same
principles you can plant states of mind
you can change your basic attitude your
daily attitude and become a more
peaceful person then obviously the the
big question that people all over the
world after two days of this we usually
do two days and three days we have a
system we do two days of open talks in a
city and then we do a three-day
intensive retreat they must leave the
city they must come with us somewhere we
gave a talk for British
Airways uh they wanted me to help with a
strike the union came and the management
came you know and they said you have 5
minutes to sell us on your system
I said I can do it you know and and then
they called us back and they said okay
we'll go to we'll go out to the
countryside with you and they brought
the vice president and they brought the
union and we we worked it out you see so
we usually do two nights of a public
talk and then anyone who wants to go
deeper we have a team of teachers and
then they help those people with their
dreams we have small breakout groups and
and they sit around tables and they say
you know I want my husband to learn to
wash a dishes
that's the most difficult Karma but
there is such a thing there is such a
thing or you know I have a physical
problem or or or you know I have credit
card problems or something like that so
we meet people individually that's how
we usually call it 2 plus three we do
this thing all over the world we are
about to leave next week for uh Paris
Hamburg Munich Stockholm Oslo and is
that it
did I forget some place huh
zor
uh and that's what we we normally do in
a city we do 2 plus three after that
we're going to China to guango and
Shenzhen Shanghai Beijing and
gendro uh so
uh people ask me that in every crowd in
every city towards the end of the second
night people will ask me can can this
system be used to create peace in the
world okay money is nice partner's good
health is great youthful energy is
exciting uh inner peace is wonderful but
but can you use can you affect a larger
system called the globe with these ideas
can can is the condition of the world
also coming from my mind and we say yes
and then how do I fix that how do I
affect that and it's very beautiful
answer okay just using the
system creates peace in the world okay
you if you use this system to achieve
some dream that you have last night I
asked everybody close their eyes for one
minute and and you were supposed to
think of some dream you have in your
life okay let's do it anyway let's just
do it again is that all right okay we're
not meditating it's not anything weird
okay uh
just I'm going to be quiet for one
minute I'm good I'm good and
um pretend I'm the wizard of O and I can
give you anything you want what would
you want tonight okay in your
life what's the one thing that you would
like to have in your life in the next
month okay what do you what and we don't
think much about it but okay I'm going
to shut up which is very
rare one minute just think what what do
you want if I could give you anything or
if this system could give you anything
what what would you like to happen in
your life
okay okay got it you don't have to tell
anybody just think about it okay and
we'll talk about it last night we talked
about I'm still doing a review of last
night real
quick I feel like I have to prove to you
that the world is coming from your mind
first
okay uh because it's a new idea for us
all right and there's a very simple way
to prove it we talked about it last
night I'm going to do it faster tonight
so that the people who came don't get
bored all right uh what is and you have
to you have to work with me okay you
can't sit there like quiet all right uh
you have to if I ask a question please
yell out something okay we learn in the
monastery if you yell loud enough they
don't notice that it's wrong all right
uh what is this thing b b pen
uh if a dog comes in here and a puppy
dog and I wave this thing in front of
the puppy dog what will they do with it
yeah they will chew with it does the
puppy dog see this as a pen no so far
you're good who's correct the human or
the
dog both yeah you're good all right uh
if I take this subject and put it on
this chair
and uh all the humans leave the room and
all the dogs also leave the room at that
time which one is
it yeah good good answer I like it all
over the world people will go or people
will go every country they go uhuh by
the way if you care and I'm not trying
to make you a Buddhist I'm not
interested in that I want you to get
whatever your wish was 5 minutes ago
okay I don't care what path you follow
it doesn't matter to me I want to see
you successful
bunch of zillionaires next year okay uh
really I don't care but if you if you're
interested that's the meaning of
emptiness in in
Buddhism that's the meaning of Kong of
emptiness okay the meaning of emptiness
is put this object on the floor on the
chair all the people go out all the dogs
go out at that time which one is it then
when you go like this you just became a
Buddhist
philosopher
okay okay it doesn't mean you close your
eyes it doesn't mean nothing matters it
doesn't mean if someone kisses you or
someone hits you it's all the same those
are all stupid okay it just
means until the person walks in or until
the dog walks in it's nothing yet it's
like a blank white screen can you do a
blank white screen your whole world is
like a blank white screen okay and your
mind is putting your mind is the
projector and it's putting things around
you okay they're all coming from your
mind all right the pen thing with the
dog proves that it proves that okay if
this were a
pen Lu give you another reality check
you
ready okay you give me your right hand
show me your right hand okay is the pen
coming from you or is the pen coming
from the pen you can do this or this
okay we have a vote this the pen is
coming from me or the pen is coming from
the pen
go yeah it's pretty
unanimous okay the pen is coming from me
why if the pen was coming from the pen
the dog would see a pen really okay it's
that simple you don't need 25 years of
diarrhea in India I just saved you
okay I just saved you all that work you
know uh it obviously that whenever you
doubt that the world is coming from you
remember the dog in the pen that's all
the world is coming from you okay all
right uh test reality check if I close
my
eyes uh could I make this something else
if this thing is coming from my mind
could I think positively and it would
change into a big diamond let's
try you
know no it's still a pen okay that's
very important it is not a matter of
willpower positive thinking doesn't get
you anywhere okay you can wish for a
week you can pray for a week you can
want for a year it won't make this a
diamond is it coming from you yes can
you close your eyes and make it whatever
you want no some other force is forcing
you to see it as a pen something in your
mind is forcing you to see it as a pen
what is that we say a seed a mental seed
there's a mental seed in your mind the
dog has a different seed all right a a
successful business person has a
different seed than an unsuccessful
business person I gave the example
yesterday of uh a building that we
bought in a bad area of New York
Tribeca and then we made made a lot of
money from it I'll give you another
example so I used to go to the India to
the monastery to study my monaster is in
India because it they all had to run
away from their country right and they
rebuilt their Monastery in in India so
now it has 4,000 monks there so I used
to go to the monastery and then we used
to buy diamonds in Mumbai because this
is the major Center for cut diamonds we
only bought cut diamonds um so I would
have to go to Mumbai to buy diamonds you
know we
bought we used 30,000 Stones a day we we
our Factory turns out 30,000 Stones a
day uh so so I would have to buy 30,000
Stones a day you know so I have to buy
big huge bags of diamonds in in India so
I'd go to India and and you know I would
call New York and say what color Diamond
you need
today this is the old the Indian phone
line it's the copper cable beneath the
ocean right and you got to yell
everybody in the office knows who you're
talking to you
go I how many diamonds you need 10,000
what color cuz they have a b c d color
right down to Z then what color m m what
m m 10,000 M color m
m then for 3 days you can't get a line
right you had to book the car you had to
Reser the call like 3 days ahead and
then if you're lucky you get the call so
I'm like okay M color if you care is a
peee color okay it's a yellow very
disgusting yellow color I'm like geez
why they need 10,000 pee color diamonds
I don't know but that's what they
ordered so that's what I'll that's what
I'll send you know so I I went and I I
worked really hard and I bought it's
hard to buy 10,000 PPC diamonds and uh
then you know you get them through
Customs by the way you always buy 10,000
you always buy 11,000 do you know why if
you need 10,000 my cord is stuck hang on
can you get my cord out here otherwise I
I have to stand okay why do you have to
buy 11,000 diamonds if you want to take
10,000 out of
India the Customs guy will count them
creatively and it will be 10 when you
finish and you're like okay all right
just give me the 10 you know yeah no he
takes the Thousand so anyway you you put
11,000 in the box and then you you you
have a wax seal and then you wire it
shut with steel wire it's in a metal box
and then you carry it on the plane and
then when you land at Kennedy they meet
you with the Brinks meet you in an
armored car and two guards are with you
all the time with guns then you come off
the plane you get in the armored car and
they take you to your office in the
armored car our office had a special
door where you went under the building
before you got out of the armored car so
you go under the building you have that
building uh we built the the basement we
remodeled the basement it could handle
about 10 FedEx trucks and the armored
car so down below there's a entrance
steel door the truck goes in you go up
in a steel elevator to the boardroom and
they say show us the diamonds there's
like eight vice presidents there and
you're like okay I got the diamonds you
know and they're they're like open up
the box and the guys are standing with
their guns and you open up the box and
you cut them steel and then you open up
the parcel you know I don't know why but
diamonds are kept in paper right it's an
Old Dutch tradition so you open the
diamonds you know and uh they all go
they're peee color I said that's what
you ask for they're like no no we didn't
never ask you for bb color diamonds I
said you said M color no no they said I
am going to call you
tomorrow and I got 10,000 P call
diamonds these are normally used in oil
well
drills they put them in the they mount
them on oil well drills nobody makes
jewelry from these things you know so
I'm like all the vice presidents are
giggling because vice presidents hate
each other and I'm like and uh everyone
leaves and I'm looking at these 10,000
stones and uh and some images Flash into
my mind this is a creative what do you
call it the throws of a creative moment
right you have these images Flash in
your mind first I see a ring and it has
five PP colored diamonds in like 18
karat super yellow gold you know more
yellow than normal European Standard you
know all yellow I see this ring five
matching PP color diamonds first flash
second flash sax Fifth Avenue exclusive
you know and then I hear golden diamond
the word golden diamond comes in my mind
you know I hear it in my mind I'm like
wow yeah we'll Market it as a golden
diamond not peee diamond and then and
then and then I see an ad in the New
York Times second page on the right side
at the bottom quarter page ad for gold
and diamond exclusive at sax pamu we
made $5
million from the PB diamonds you know
and uh you know so the next board
meeting was uh Mike can you go get
10,000 more of those things you know and
uh it was a mistake you know the whole
thing was a mistake and the stones were
worthless they're just good for oil well
drills you know so the big question is
why did those thoughts flash through my
mind you see uh why does a creative
moment happened to you it could be an
education you see why do you get a
Insight uh into some problem with
education with a school like you have a
sudden insight into how to fix a school
or or how to have a cool program in a
school where do flashes of insight come
from where' it
go okay go like
this they come from you okay really
honestly I'm trying to turn you on to
something that I use my whole life now I
don't have any business training don't
like business I hate accounting I don't
like marketing I don't like selling
things but but with this knowledge I
made a $200 million company okay and
then I quit it and I'm just doing other
things just to prove I could do it you
see what I mean and you can do anything
you want a creative flashes you want to
be creative that's also coming from your
mind okay moments of creativity can be
planted in your mind and you can have
more of them next year than you have
this year and you can be the most
creative educator or or government uh
person or organizational leader or you
can plan sorry moments of creativity
okay you just plant them in your mind
and your mind changes and becomes more
creative it's it's exciting it's cool
and I'm not try I don't care if you you
should learn what I'm saying take it
home use it for yourself okay you don't
have to join anything I don't want your
picture my picture in your house uh it's
not very cool uh I don't care take what
I'm talking about take it home and use
it in your life and you never have to
report back I don't care okay sometimes
a person you have her name uh Kaplan
Taylor sometimes a person will come to
me like a year later this is Linda
Kaplan Taylor she was sitting here okay
in New York during a talk not too long
ago she's a secretary in an ad company
right and she's like I'm like talking
about how to plant creative moments you
know I'm like giving her the same talk
and she's like this you know and then
like a year later someone calls me you
know and they said I said what they said
some ladyes on The Today Show talking
about your book and I like turn on the
TV you know and here's here she is you
know and they're like so Linda how did
you make a a billion doll company I'm
like billion dollar that's four times
bigger than my company and then
uh and she's like oh I used this book
The Diamond Cutter you know I met this
guy he gave a talk about creativity I
started using it I quit my job as a
secretary I I rented an apartment in the
East Village a one room junkie apartment
and I started an ad agency you can check
online it's Linda it's Kaplan Taylor
advertising and she invented the toys
are us thing and all this other stuff
the duck on afflac she invented all
these things uh because she was sitting
here and then she planted all those
things and now she's got a billion
dollar company do you have a building
that's her building okay on Madison okay
in the 50s it's like I call her up I
said let's do lunch she said I'm
busy but thank you g you know I'm well
yeah so
how it happens all over the so that's
that my dream for you you don't have to
report back I'll see you on the Today's
Show okay I don't care take it and run
take it and run with it you don't have
to join anything you I don't have to see
you again just use it in your life and
that's all I care you know so four steps
I'll say the four steps again you want
to know how to plant a mental seed okay
this comes from ancient Tibetan wisdom
okay and China also in China it's called
Abid Dharma and they're called she s so
say the Tibetan word is good luck and it
makes me look smart ready
she s
s t she
s we talked about it yesterday I'll
review quickly because it's not fair to
the people who did come last night to
make them sit through it again she means
uh decide what you want in your life I
would like to make a breakthrough in
this education problem in my town the
the children are not achieving a certain
level or something like that I would
like to have a breakthrough in that or I
would like to do a breakthrough with
women in China or something I want a
breakthrough in my personal life or you
know I want to breakthrough with my
partner you know we used to be really
intimate we used to to have really
exciting times together and now it just
seems like boring and physically boring
and emotionally boring and it's all the
all the excitement is gone I that's my
goal tell me what your you decide step
number one it's on that little piece of
paper you have okay did they get does
everybody have thater there's a tiny
little thing that you're supposed to put
in your refrigerator okay anyone need
can I hold it up sure thank you it's got
a little tiger in the bottom we use it
in China a lot that's why okay uh this
came from
Shanghai okay anybody doesn't have one
you want one you know it's for your
refrigerator tape it on your
refrigerator okay it's the four steps
it's she number one decide what you want
here's the trick okay here's the trick
to planting a seed number two you must
find another human being who wants the
same thing you want okay you must find
another person somewhere in your life in
your family your
co-workers
um anyone who wants the same thing that
you want you cannot plant a seed without
another person it's not possible you
cannot bounce a basketball without a
floor okay it's not possible you can try
I don't know what will happen probably
just you lose the ball right it goes
somewhere
you need a floor to bounce the
basketball to plant a mental seed you
cannot do it without other people it's
not possible and they must be in need
they must be someone who needs something
okay uh someone who needs what you need
you know I I want to I want my husband
to be more affectionate then you must
find a person who's starving for
affection from their husband or or from
their children or someone else you you
must find another person with the same
need okay that's principle number two
you cannot use this system without
another person then people will say to
me I don't know anybody who needs some
affection then I will say you check for
24 hours and you get back to me and then
they say I found 10 you know the next
day I get this email I found 10 you know
how did you find 10 that you didn't know
about the day for I never paid
attention to the condition of the people
around me I wasn't aware that every one
of my friends had the same problem with
their husband you know because I never
asked them or I wasn't listening you see
what I mean so you will discover step
number two you will discover that people
have been expressing their needs to you
all along and you weren't listening you
see what I mean so you will find 10
people who want the same thing by the
way it doesn't have to be exactly the
same name if you want a zillion dollars
and they want a gazillion that's okay
all right that's the same thing okay uh
something similar you must find a person
and you must make a plan okay normally
in we would do two nights and then we
would do a three-day Retreat we would
take you out in the country somewhere
and uh there are three parts of the
second one called say
Kong if you don't say anything I'm going
home
Kong
these are three aspects of Step number
two okay and we it's more detail and you
can go for we have 12 levels of this
training you're getting the first half
of the first level we have 12 levels
that we go through we're about to leave
in Hamburg we're they're up to five
they're the highest in the world right
now Singapore is close beijing's on
three uh so
anyway the second part of number two is
that you must make a plan for this other
person it's good intentions plant some
seeds but not much okay you don't get
much credit for Good Intentions you have
to make a concrete plan for the help
you're going to give this other person
you must okay and I suggest a place and
a time and I always tell people take
them out to Starbucks and talk to them
you know take them out to Starbucks and
talk to them about what about the
affection problem with their husband
okay then what am I supposed to say just
ask them you say I have a problem with
my husband and maybe you have the same
problem can you help me tell you know
it's a better way to act don't say I
heard your husband's a creep let's go
out to Starbuck you know say be a more
finesse have more finesse you know say
you know I have a problem frankly I have
a problem and I I want more affection
and I think you might want it too let's
go out and help each other let's let's
go out once a week to Starbucks I like
Starbucks because it's neutral territory
you know you know you you're not going
to their house and they're not coming to
your house so if they want to get up and
walk out they can and if you want to get
up and walk out you can you know you're
like free right I like it I like
Starbucks for that reason it's a big
social thing right Starbucks is
wonderful uh so anyway take them the
plan second part of number two make a
plan number three is what
duh take them to Starbucks okay just
take them out do you have to solve their
problems no can you solve their problems
no why not you have the same
problem if you knew how to fix your
husband you would have done it already
who are you to tell them how to fix
their husband you know uh but it's the
intention intention is 90% of all seats
that's the Kong that I just mentioned
Kong means if your heart is to want to
help them if your heart is pouring out
to them I want to help you out I'm not
capable of helping you out I have the
same problem but let's try it's that
words in your mouth let's try plant the
seed okay that let's try plant the seed
okay you don't have to solve other
problems I'll ask you a difficult
question okay you're already mental seed
experts is it even possible to help
another
person get a more affectionate husband
is it possible to change another
person will your words cause their
husband to be more
affectionate yes or
no does everyone who give advice to
another person succeed in making their
their husband more affectionate no uh if
they don't succeed why did they
fail yeah cuz that person's seats that
person had their own seat
you cannot control other people's seeds
okay you have to learn
that only the person can plant their own
seeds you cannot loan seeds to another
person okay it's very interesting you
must do your own Good Deeds no one else
can loan you some good some extra good
deeds they have okay you must be kind
yourself and you must serve someone else
yourself no one else can put a senor
your mind you can't make anybody else
anything it's not possible can I make
you
happy no I cannot you know I can teach
you how to plant a
seed but then you have to plant a seed
you see what I mean I can't plant a seed
for you each person must be kind to
other people and that plants a seed for
them but I cannot give you seeds I can
show you how to plant them I can I can
field your questions which we'll do
after the break okay so you stay away
wait uh after all that junk food um I
can field your questions about seeds but
I can't plant them for you you must do
it yourself you must take someone out to
Starbucks nobody else can do it for you
okay that's one thing you have to do
step number three you must help them you
must actually help them if you don't
nothing will happen Okay I guarantee
nothing will
happen
these are the four principles of karma
in the ancient books means you do
something good you get something good
you do something bad you get something
bad you cannot get Thorns from grapes
from thistles or figs from Thorns or
whatever it was okay if you plant a
mango you ain't going to get a
grapefruit okay it's that simple first
law of karma this isn't part of this
class but anyway it's okay second law of
karma it always gets bigger it always
gets bigger help another person for half
an hour to plant seeds to make their
husband more affectionate your husband
will become more affectionate for a
week okay because of the second law of
karma all seeds expand exponentially
every 24 hours a seed within the
subconscious doubles in power at the end
of a week it's how many ninbo where are
you
Eric a thousand how many at the end of a
month
you over two billion okay the P the
power never never pass up a chance to do
a small
kindness because within a month that
power has is two billion times stronger
according to this ancient teachings
never pass up a chance to give some you
know you have like the last piece of a
chocolate chip cookie give it to
somebody no I'm not kidding like like
jump on little chances someone's trying
to find a parking space you know you
know like that you know give the parking
space you know no a person who really
understands this system is is looking
for little chances to do things you
because they always grow third principle
of
karma means uh if oh that's what I was
trying to get to if you don't take them
to Starbucks nothing's going to happen
if you don't plant a seed your why would
you expect your husband to change you
see are you going to talk them into
being affectionate do you want to know
what a hug feels like when you've argued
your way into a hug you
know you've proven to your husband why
you should have a hug now you did I
prove to you I need a hug yes okay give
me the hug like it doesn't feel that
good all because they don't want to hug
you you just talk them into it say Lea
means uh unless you provide someone else
with a way
to get affection you cannot get
affection yourself it cannot happen it
will never happen your situation will
never change unless you help someone
else not possible the fourth law by the
way if it appears to happen what do you
think is the answer to that if it
appears that a person's husband suddenly
becomes more affectionate after not
being affectionate for a long time and
you didn't do anything to make someone
else's husband more affectionate why do
you think it
happens why do random acts of affection
sudden why does why do some people's
husbands suddenly change without using
this
system it's an older scene it's an older
seed they were affectionate to someone a
long time ago okay and that seed's only
just now uh opening
where in your mind in your own mind okay
the see is opening in your own mind and
the husband becomes more affectionate
okay who plants a seed I do how at
Starbucks what records the scene my
awareness of my attempt to help the
other person records the see my
awareness of my own words of my own
gestures of my own feelings towards them
my awareness of me trying to help
someone else is what plants a sin okay
it's very cool that's what plants a seed
in your subconscious there's always a
witness there okay the flip side of that
is if you want to do something bad it
doesn't help to go in your room and
close the
door because it's always recorded
by you if you're aware that you're doing
something wrong it has been recorded
okay you can say there's a guy up at the
ply Gates who is that I forget St Peter
he's recording everything in this system
you you can St Peter can go to Starbucks
and relax because your own mind is
recording everything you do okay and it
doesn't miss anything it not a single
second you can have a moment's
irritation at someone your mind will
record it and it will come back to you
that's the fourth law of karma it will
always come back anything you do
anything you say and more powerfully
anything you think will come back to you
always there's no exceptions no one can
cut you slack no one can say oh we'll
cancel that one you know that was a
tragedy you didn't do that on purpose
that's okay we'll let you go on that one
you know according to this system
there's no such thing you must
experience all kindnesses the results of
all kindnesses and all harms you have
done to others we'll come back to you
now people get concerned they're
like uh there is a way to um
short circuit of SE we'll talk about it
before the end of the night okay because
I owe you that if I don't see you for a
couple months I owe you that because we
all have right my one of my high school
friends is here we all make mistakes
when we're 16 okay or 17 I don't know
when was that never mind uh we all make
some mistakes big mistakes in our life
small things that hurt other people a
lot then obviously if you're going to
use the system you have to learn how to
take that seed out or or diffuse it
technically you cannot take the seed out
but you can what do you call it in
tibetan they say a saon tick it means to
Scorch a a seed like to apply fire to a
seed and then something happens to the
seed it ruins the seed
um you put too much heat on a seed with
a fire or Flame or like a candle flame
on a small seed the seed is still there
you see that's the point the seed is
still in your mind but it will never
grow it has
been cauterized something has broken
inside of the seed the the seed is still
whole it looks good it looks like a
regular seed but it has been um ruined
it has been somehow sterilized sterilize
is goodal neutralize is good
I feed my
finches you have finches in FL that
yellow little yellow banana colored guys
I feed them niger seed niger seed is a
thorn seed that comes from India it's
illegal to import it without radiating
it so they bring it in 25 lbs bags and
they radiate it you know and uh it it
does something to the seed then the ones
that the birds drop don't create Thorn
bushes all over my garden you see what I
mean so whatever you want to call that
sterilize them or something de de
deactivate them anyway there's a way and
I'll teach it before the end of the
night if we don't spend the whole time
on me trying to find out word okay
uh so that's the basic system for
planting a seed okay and you can plant
anything you can plant creativity in
your own mind you can plant youthful
energy you can plant uh Financial
Independence you can plant a peaceful
world and we have to talk that before
tonight we have a lot of jobs because I
won't see you for a while we have to
discuss how would you
change the nature of the world itself to
let no poverty uh no no war like is it
possible is that also coming from me
like is is the state of Iraq and
Afghanistan is that also coming from me
and we have to talk about that before
the night is over okay I have not found
the seed for hair uh uh but I'm checking
the
scriptures uh okay so we'll get to that
all right so I think we take a break 7
years pages of ancient
philosophy they studied 10,000 pages of
these books they had 300 classroom hours
and seven years of training before they
went into retreat but there was an
incident of domestic violence and we had
to take action I think as a board in the
University there's been I think 50
deaths in the United States in
universities this year shootings and
other and we just didn't feel like we
should condone it or we should allow it
and they refused to uh cooperate they
refused to even talk to us at all when
we tried to do an inquiry so we asked
them to do and that's the bottom line of
it and then the Press got a got de
magazine and and a lot of uh you you
know uh what do you call
that Daily News and things like that and
they made it into some weirdo thing but
it it isn't it's a very there
are the people in Retreat there there's
a medical doctor MD there's two Pas
there's a registered nurse there's a PhD
in computer science there's a PhD in
biology there's a PhD in
um something
I don't remember there's a commercial
airline pilot there's a published
military historian they're all serious
people and they're good people I mean
thepress Got a Hold
again and it became something very
strange so I'm sorry about that it was
very sad for us um but I think any
University would have
have had to do the same thing you can't
allow violence on
cus especially in America right
now
[Applause]
first of all thank you so much
for
se you how do
work yeah I think uh we cannot plant
seeds for another person what I mean we
we can teach people how to plant seeds
but you can't force it on people you can
say uh if you would like to have
violence is not a part of this system if
you want what's the cause of violence in
the world you know what is in the
Scripture it
say this is
Suns the cause of violence in the world
is small violence that I have done
myself and which I continue to do on a
daily basis I say small things to people
which are hurtful I uh I cut in front of
another person in traffic I uh get
irritated at the lady at the counter in
the grocery store
then how can these be causes of violence
in my world I I'm doing small unkind
things to other people you know
then are you proposing that this has
caused Iraq or Afghanistan in my world
and the answer is yes why because of
that principle that seeds double every
24 hours okay you can do a small act of
violence towards someone and if you
don't take that seed out or you don't
deal with that seed you will see
violence around you and it's coming from
you the violence you see in the world
according to this is coming from us and
and then you get depressed you know
you're like are you saying I'm
responsible for Iraq yes and Afghanistan
yes and all the other violence and
sadness I see in the world and is it me
and the answer is yes it is and then you
can get
uh what do you call it you can lose hope
about that but but we are trained by our
teachers to look at it the other way you
know now I have a way to change the
world I can personally affect the
violence in the
world by not engaging in violence myself
in small acts of violence so then I have
to observe my own life and I must be
careful not to commit violence any kind
of
violence so people ask me is what's the
event at your University caus who who
whose's fault then in the end I have to
say
what my fault okay why did I say
violence uh because I have I have
committed small acts of violence
constantly every day all day towards
other people UN Small uncan acts build
up into things like
Afghanistan so it's very interesting
that's what that's our belief so in the
end I have to examine myself and and I
have to be a more peaceful
person cool it's a hard answer but it's
a good answer yeah I want to know what
influence does your comma your
individual Kaa have on your your it was
okay you know and then uh when I got to
toet to study
withans they were very clear that
conception begins at the moment sorry
life begins at the moment of conception
I'm not trying to convince you that it's
not my goal and it's not my business
your body is your own your your life is
your own I'm just
reporting what my llama my llama that I
lived with for 25 years who became like
my father and I loved him like my father
okay uh out of concern for me he said
you have to get rid of that seed you
have to take care of that seed you know
and I felt it inside me I felt it I'm
not trying to convince you about
abortion it's your own life it's your
own business myself I felt something
wrong I felt like I have to clean this
it doesn't hurt to clean it just in case
okay so uh I said okay tell tell me what
I have to do and he said there are four
steps to clean any past mistake anything
you ever did to hurt anyone you can
clean it okay clean is technically you
cannot remove a seed from your mind
until it opens it's not possible there's
no such
thing the universe runs by A Perfect
Justice you will always get back exactly
what you have done to others you cannot
escape this Justice in this system
there's there no exceptions
but you can radiate the Niger
SE okay you can uh and The Diamond
Cutter it it teaches the method the
Ching oldest book in the world oldest
book with the DAT printon uh it tells
you the diamond cover Sutra has a
chapter about how to
disable a an old mistake so that it
doesn't come back to you okay it will go
off with a Fizz you
know and it's done you know you're like
you know I didn't have that car accident
or I didn't get cancer you know and uh
so here's the four steps okay you should
know it all right just try it it doesn't
hurt do a little house cleaning you know
we all have some things we did that with
mistakes and it's good to admit it okay
number
one uh
think about the pen just think about the
pen if I could find it all right just
think about the pen that's all just
think about it think about where things
are coming from that's all okay is it
coming from itself or is it coming from
me it's coming from me don't take it as
a what do you call article of this new
religion there is no new religion I
don't care what you are doesn't matter
to me it's it's not faith we proved it
with the dog okay that's all things must
be coming from you because why because
you don't want to chew it and you don't
start slobbering every time I hold it
on it must be coming from from you okay
that's all think about that okay
everything is coming from you that's
step number one to
what disabling in all bad SE dis sing in
Old B scene I saw a movie once and I
can't help mentioning it and it's kind
of naughty okay but that's how I am uh
it was John Travolta it was a bad movie
in his later time right after the Disco
movies and uh called Broken Arrow and
there's an atomic bomb about to go off
and he's straddling it and trying to
pull the wires out and I'm like when
that goes off that's going to hurt right
right where he's got it where he's got
it you know they had a very primal thing
like he was I'm like damn that's going
to hurt you know and
uh and then at the last minute he pulls
out the right wire and nothing it
doesn't go off that's what we want to do
with the abortion seed or whatever it
was for you we want to reach in and
disable the seed okay is there a way to
disable a seed can you remove the seed
no it will stay there forever but it
will never go off or it will go off with
a fiz okay so step number one just think
about the pen step number
two just consider what will happen if
you
don't okay if you if it's true that the
power of a negative seed doubles every
hours okay then where is it now after
two years or after 3 years you know what
will happen to me when that seed opens
okay just think about it you know just
think about it that's all that's
supposed
to get you to have a a feeling of in we
call it intelligent regret there's no
word for Guilt in Tibetan or SRP I'm not
aware of a word for Guilt okay there's
no word in those languages for I'm a bad
person like that you rather step number
two is like you feel
empowered I can I can can kill this
thing and I'm going to do it like dirty
hering you know make Monday you know I'm
going to take care of this te you know
like that it's a kind of uh what do you
call it in tibetan they call it Nagel
Nagel means uh I'm the king but it means
confidence it means I can deal with this
thing you're not paralyzed by guilt you
are empowered by the knowledge that you
can kill this SI okay so step number two
is like I got to deal with this SI I
can't just let it go go on in the hopes
that it will never come back to me cuz
there's no such
thing just there's no such thing as a as
a harmful action which does not come
back to hurt you it will come back so
with that knowledge you're not scared
you're you're like I got to get rid of
this thing before before it opens I got
to get this thing out of
my guts I got to get rid of this thing
so that's step number two before this
thing gets out of hand I got to refuse
it now and you feel like right I can do
it you know that's step number two step
number three is the most important there
is no more important step to removing a
negative stat there is no more important
step if you don't remember the other
three just remember number three okay
what is number
three uh you make a commitment not to do
it again and that destroys the power of
the SE very cool very interesting you
make a commitment to yourself or you
they say it's very powerful to make it
to someone else it could be someone you
know it's very powerful to say it out
loud to anybody it doesn't matter uh
anybody I I promise I'm not going to do
that thing again in my case I I said I
will never be involved with that again I
became a monk I'm safe you like that
just won't happen you know it can't
happen you see like so make a commitment
I will never do that thing again now the
great scriptures of
time and again we have a project for 25
years we have been typing in those
scriptures um we've done half a million
Pages the Tibetan refugees are typing
like all day for 25 years and now it's
online you know it's 20 500,000 pages of
of scriptures we have 150 years to go
that's how vast the Tibetan wisdom is we
have 150 years we are planned to go for
five more
Generations we've already been through
two generations okay uh the grandkids of
our original operators are tying uh so
anyway and the computers are from 1985
also that's another problem
that's where most of my personal money
went to took millions of dollars but we
fed them thousands of refuges so
anyway uh the great books say You must
make a commitment and then the books
have a small crint on number three okay
what's the small
friend what would you like what seed
would you like to
destroy I got mad at my husband
yesterday okay will you make a
commitment yes I want to remove the
scene otherwise people around me will be
angry with with me for weeks I want to
remove that scene so will you make the
commitment yes what's the
commitment I'll never get angry at my
husband again come on you know like
these great llas will be up there and
they'll say k come on you know hopeless
man you're going to get mad at him
before this evening is over you know
on the evening you made the promise
you'll get angry with him again before
you go to bed it's sure you know so then
the great books say make a time limit
set a time limit okay and with things
like anger it can be a day or three days
I I always tell people make a commitment
not to get angry at your husband or say
something bad to him on a Friday didn't
come on a DCI 3day Retreat and leave
your phone at home and you know you
won't see him until Monday so because
you will make a new negative suit you
see if you
overcommit uh you just St take a step
back you see you then you've made a new
negative steam uh so they say set a time
limit okay I I will with an abortion
that's easy for the rest of my life but
for getting angry at your
husband until I see him
again pick something me and I'm not
kidding and the power is still good the
power is good but you cannot break that
commitment if you break it then the
whole deal is off okay so make a
reasonable commitment okay step number
three is make a reasonable commitment
for your circumstances whatever your
circumstances are step number
four step number three is negative if
you think about it it's a commitment not
to do something step number four is
positive I make a commitment to do
something positive to balance the the
action some balancing thing okay in my
case I made a commitment to teach the
children in my neighborhood and I taught
them for 15 years okay I taught the
children in my neighborhood for 15 years
and I bribed them to come to class with
I was living in a Buddhist temple and
they were all Buddhist they were all
Mongolians so I I made a deal with the
parents and they came to class some of
the parents came to class and for 15
years I taught them okay so you make
some
positive commitment uh which is the
opposite you see what I mean in my
belief I killed a child so then I must
give children life I must do something
to serve children right so you make a
what do you call makeup activi
something to make up for the karma okay
if you do those four things you will get
the signs that that seed is gone okay
I'll tell you the signs so you enough
then you can get mad at your husband
again you know just kidding
uh there's two signs that a seed is is
has
left number one it will F right the bomb
will go f you will have a a brief
violent negative occurrence in your life
uh the Buddha in the jinghan Jing
mentions a an an extreme migraine for
two to three days a person who has never
had a migraine will have an extremely
painful migraine for two or three days
and then suddenly it's gone and the
seed's power has been you you would have
been in a car accident or you would have
gotten breast cancer something and you
get a violent headache from two or three
days that's uh then if you know about
seeds you're happy like Yay I got the
headache you know and the power of the
sced is just you know it's I don't know
how would you say that in English it's
uh it's fizzing out just tiny little
resolve has come to me I was supposed to
be in a car and now look I I just got
into a three day MRA and then and then
the second s sign that the scene is
finished is that you will suddenly feel
very light and happy as if someone has
taken a burden off you that you've been
carrying all that time and you didn't
notice you see I mean you carry those
seeds you carry those burdens in your
life and you don't and you get used to
being like this and it becomes part of
you you you have it on your mind you
have the depth in my case it's on your
heart it's Weighing on your heart and
then when the seat is taken out suddenly
you feel like 10 years younger or
something and you you feel like someone
has freed you from something you didn't
know you have you didn't know you were
carrying it and suddenly you feel like
someone took a huge burden off you and
you feel joyful and happy and light in
your life and that's the second sign
okay so when those two signs happen
that's enough and then our llamas
say it's done with and don't think about
it and don't ever think about it again
you can forget it it's over you know the
whole thing is over I can talk about it
because for me it's over I took care of
it I'm clean of it I don't intend to do
it again and I feel happy and for me
it's a nonevent now it's it's gone and
my llama heard about uh what do you call
that in the cafe church at the last
moment uh it's called last bre some
priest comes to a dying person and says
do you have anything to confess at the
last minute when my llama heard about
that he got excited he was really happy
he say oh good custom good custom you
know that's fantastic that's so smart
you know clean at the last minute if you
know someone who's dying my dad was
dying uh from cancer I was in his home I
watched more football games that month
than I'll ever watch a gamer before cuz
he couldn't do anything else he was
dying I made him orange juice which was
all he could take and I watched him die
and then I thought I asked my teacher
you know he's cut all these seeds you
know these old Bad Seeds he said what
kind of seeds and my dad was on a
submarine in World War II he lied to the
Navy he said he was 16 he was 15 he got
on a submarine at age 15 and his job was
deck Gunner which you never used the gun
on top of a submarine cuz you're always
underwater but if you torpedo another
boat and all those guys are swimming in
the water you come up and you shoot them
all helpless people in the middle of the
Pacific you shoot them and that was his
job you know he was assigned at age 15
to shoot hopeless people drowning in in
the middle of th000 miles of sea and he
couldn't get it off so then you can
trick people okay sit the dam as near
dying and say you know Dad tell me about
that Navy thing tell me about what you
did again and then he told me and then I
said would you do that now I mean would
you ever do that again he said no no I
would never do it again step number
tree you see so you can trick people you
know you get their mind in a certain you
take their mind to a certain place and
then you said would you do that again
and he said no Then I then he can die
you see then he can die without it so
it's very important help people to let
go of something negative they've done
before they die okay and that's how you
remove a a bad seat and you should try
you should do it tonight you should do
it okay tonight you should do it okay
whenever it sees you have you should do
it and you feel so Harmony okay so
that's just like a bonus thing I wasn't
supposed to talk about that tonight
uh
one more question or two more questions
if you have say what it is you want I
want Focus number two find someone else
who needs focus and give it to them um
how do you give someone Focus about
interrupting other
people okay be if you're interested in
gaining some kind of focus in your life
if you would like to be able to have a
focused powerful meditative State of
Mind
it's very interesting in tibc we have a
very very sophisticated methods of
meditation we are trained for many years
uh and that's actually DCI level three
we take you through the traditional
training of how to develop a powerful
mind we take business people through the
traditional training for developing a
powerful State of Mind there are nine
states of Mind there are eight antidotes
there are five traditional problems
there are four modes that it go through
it's very beautiful it's all on this
beautiful carved ancient carved painting
and we take business people like in
Germany we took a whole group through
this uh focus
training but in the end if you want the
bottom
line uh what creates Focus the seed for
focus is to be kind to other
people it's morality it's ethics it's
very strange okay
what the Tibetans
decided after a thousand years was that
maintaining basic ethical
standards create Focus it's the karma
for Focus okay what are ethical
standards it's the same in Tibet as it
is in judeo Christian tradition okay
there are 10 guidelines uh number one
I'll give them to you real fast you're
getting everything tonight uh we got 15
more minutes hang in there and I'm sorry
to overwhelm you but I won't see you for
a while
so it's important if you want to learn
to meditate there are many many things
to learn posture how to hold your eyes
how to hold your teeth how to hold your
tongue how to hold your shoulders your
pelvis what kind of seat to have how to
prepare the room you know all this thing
but it boils down
to keep 10 codes of conduct and you will
have
meditation what are the 10 codes of
conduct number one respect life respect
life don't kill don't harm also animals
don't kill animals okay don't kill
respect life every living being loves
their life respect it number one uh
number two respect other people's
property okay don't steal things public
public property is is the most uh
difficult people who will never PP on
their own toilet seat at home will shoot
all over the bathroom in a public
bathroom I don't know what that is I
don't know why that is but for boys it's
pretty weird uh so with public uh
respect other people's property okay the
roads have been paid for by
everyone uh if you litter if you throw
garbage on the
street technically you are harming
everyone who paid taxes to build that
street it's very subtle it's very
profound we have to respect other
people's property okay number two number
three respect other people's Partners
okay um respect people who are in a
committed relationship okay is it wrong
to hit on a girl who's available no it's
fine uh is it wrong to hit on a person
who's in a committed relationship yes
it's a very very bad karma and and it
will hurt you bad karma is defined by
the way by what hurts you later not by
what it hurts somebody else it hurts you
okay so number three is uh respect other
people's
Partnerships in Tibet they have a
guideline never say or do anything to
another person's partner that you
wouldn't do if their partner and your
partner weren't there at the
time we're there at the time sorry got
it always pretend your partner standing
next to you when you engage in a
conversation with someone of the oppos
opposite sex got it that's the guideline
and it's not you it makes you happy okay
these are not what do you
call rules that you must follow No One's
Gonna what do you call it punish you
there's no such thing
your life will not be happy if you do
these things that's all you won't get
what you want if you want to have a
beautiful partner don't hit on other
people's partners then you'll get a
better one it's just good sense common
sense it's a cool system okay whatever
person you're attracted to who's already
married respect their relationship a
better one will come duh you know like
just get it you know you can get a
better one
respect the other person's partnership
and if you suppose you get the person
suppose you're able to take another
person's wife away or husband away what
will
happen according to this principles
someone will take them away you know
they'll cheat on you it's like the
dumbest thing you can do what you going
to take someone's partner yeah I like
them then someone else is going to take
him in 2 years or you'll get divorced in
2 years and divorce number three divorce
you know there's no end okay anyway we
can talk about that next one what number
are we on four four you're good all
right uh tell the truth speak truthfully
okay speak truthfully I'll tell you the
standard of Truth in Tibet and it's
difficult what does it mean to speak the
truth someone says to you uh what kind
of Refreshments that they have at the
program tonight that everyone works so
hard to provide is's very
kind it's so nice that they didn't have
cheap potato chips and stuff they have
nice cheeses and cool stuff so someone
says to you what did they what kind of
Refreshments did they have at the
program tonight then into your mind Pops
a
picture of what Refreshments they had
tonight at the program right a picture
pops into your
mind with your words in the next minute
you must communicate to the other person
in such a way that the same picture
rises in their
mind that's truth and that's difficult
okay that's truth right truth means by
your words another person gets the same
image in their mind that you have in
your mind perfect picture of all the
refreshments you see what I mean
accurate uh video the same got it that's
truth it's
difficult why tell the
truth people around you will be truthful
for the rest of your
life okay seeds
multiply be truthful for six weeks enjoy
the results for the rest of your life
okay it's cool just everyone around you
is honest all the time it's very
refreshing okay okay number two don't
split up other people with your speech
bring people together struggle to bring
people together you hear that this
person's is not getting along with that
person make it your business to try to
bring them back together you see what I
mean uh that's number five okay uh
number six
is don't say things that hurt other
people's feelings okay um be careful I I
make jokes I make a lot of jokes and I
hurt people's feelings people inform me
later that it wasn't funny and it hurt
my feelings you know so you have to
watch people's faces
as you speak to them even if you're
telling a joke and make sure you're not
hurting their feelings okay that's
number six six number
seven is
to waste
speech to waste words with other people
uh did you hear about uh Brad Pit's
latest Scandal you know and useless talk
I guess you could call it useless talk
avoid useless talk don't waste the
precious moments of other people's lives
with gosip or stupid things from the
national inquire People magazine things
like that like don't waste other
people's time say when you
speak you only have so many words in
your life it's finite you will only
speak so many words in your life do you
really want to spend uh 2,000 of those
words words on Brad Pit's latest problem
you know what I mean and then the answer
is no I don't want to waste my words
that way your words are limited the
words you will be allowed to speak in
this life are are numbered use them
wisely okay uh number eight now number
eight yeah um this is
difficult
uh when something good happens to
somebody else you feel
unhappy that's number eight by the way
the last three are by far the most
serious okay someone else gets a
promotion someone else finds a beautiful
partner somebody else is wearing an
elegant dress tonight and you feel
like you feel unhappy about other
people's success okay I don't know why
we do that it's a sad thing we are
incapable
often of enjoying other people's
successes and that's number eight and
it's it it's very
serious Lord
Buddha taught
84,000 negative actions 84,000 in the
scriptures these are the top
10 these are the top 10 it means we must
be doing it almost constantly all day we
must be doing that look her dress
dang you know I was in yoga class today
dang look at that guy look at his
headstand dang you know then you just
did number eight okay it's a negative uh
eight is very tricky hard for me it's
almost like jealousy right or something
like that number nine is
uh a fascination with other people's
problems it's the opposite of number
eight in a way you see oh look you know
they're having trouble look the tragedy
happened with their family or or look oh
it's like what do you call it when
you're looking at a car
accident rubber neck yeah it's
rubbernecking it's like this art
fascination with the problems of famous
people or normal people oh look she got
cancer or oh look uh they they broke up
you know oh look you know and we have
this uh it's not that we are evil and we
are not happy that they are suffering
but we have this unhealthy interest in
it we are it's you see it uh when you
check out at the grocery store all those
magazines they are a long it's painful
to go check out I try to concentrate on
the gum you know because uh there's six
there's six uh magazines about people's
somebody's plastic surgery fail and
they you know you should sorry about
that you know it's not something to take
joy in you see what I mean so we have
this problem and then I think we're done
for the night okay uh oh one more thing
I have for you after that the 10th one
and the most serious one is to believe
that anything in the world is not coming
from
you
okay oh my husband is my husband doesn't
show me affection it's coming from me no
no no
of the pen maybe but not my
husband what applies to the pen applies
to every event in your life and every
person you ever met in your life was an
exact mirror of your
personality okay every irritating person
you ever met was coming exactly from you
precisely from you the ratio of
irritating to nice people in your life
is exactly the ratio of irrit inness and
being niess inside you okay people are
like
e okay that's number 10 okay number 10
is realize where the world is coming
from and it's coming from you it can be
either
depressing or it can be it can fill you
with hope you know I can change the
world I have the power to change oh if
the world's coming from me I don't like
the Iraq thing I'm going to take care of
that okay you have the power all right
behind the
power some lady asked me what how do I
get a partner I said go to a nursing
home you know help a lonely person
because that's the seed for meeting
someone who will remove your loneliness
right a person who's interested in a new
relationship uh must locate a lonely
person it's your job okay you must
locate a lonely many many many people
have asked me many many people I have
talked many many people have gotten
beautiful Partners okay where at the
nursing home okay and it works I want to
say two things about that and then we're
done okay number
one many of the people I I taught that
thing when they got their partner they
stopped visiting the person in the
nursing
home okay and that's a bad idea why
every hour that you spend with you new
partner is using up seeds in your mind
you you have a debit card that was
charged up at the nursing home and every
hour you spend with your new partner you
are losing seats because they create him
got it they are being used up every hour
he's with you so a smart person would go
with their new partner to the nursing
home we call it
reinvestment reinvestment
if you make a million dollars using this
system what should you do with half of
it give it again don't sit on it don't
sit on it give it to somebody else turn
it over make it an upward fler okay
don't stop you can't stop okay you have
to keep going then this other person
said uh how's that going to change the
world you made the claim and this is the
last thing I say I
promise you made the claim at the
beginning of these two nights that the
very use of this system for my personal
goals would create peace in the world
would change the world the whole
world just run that bias how that works
okay you ready we got two minutes it
might take a few minutes more three
minutes
uh I always tell this joke okay this is
a joke okay but it's for real
some lady told me okay I got the boy he
came I planted the boy at the nursing
home and he came in she was in a yoga
class and he walked in and they got
married I officiated at the ceremony I
helped her plant him and then I married
them it was awesome you know and it was
very cool and then uh she says well what
do I do now I said when he first when
she first got I said now you got to take
care of the world now you have to change
the world use him to change the world
she's like what do you mean cuz
everybody wants to be
Spider-Man everybody wants to change the
world why do they make X-Men Iron Man
Spider-Man Fantastic Four Avengers
four what is it why do we are fascinated
by superheroes Wonder
Woman uh we want to be done that's why
those movies still make us superhero
movie have an anonymous kid in the
Transformers save the world three times
in a
row everyone will come because they want
to do it everybody wants to be the
anonymous kid who saves the world learn
this system and you automatically have
that power learn this system and the
magic spider bit you and you will be
Spider-Man you see just use this system
to get the things you want and you are
automatically SA serving the world
explain that so I told this lady when
she first got the boy this's a cool
thing I said call up all your
girlfriends tell them you have to meet
them at the restaurant at 7:00 she's
like okay okay I have four or five
girlfriends I said tell them to meet you
at the restaurant at 7 o' she said okay
what next call your new boyfriend his
name was Stefan okay you guys know him
call your new boyfriend uh tell him to
come to your apartment at 7:00 she's
like don't you mean 6:30 I'm like no
7 okay where am I supposed to be at the
apartment what are we going to do at the
apartment while they're waiting in the
restaurant duh give him three big
glasses of
water she said what give him three big
glasses of water don't worry I'll
explain when he finishes the water then
go to the
restaurant and then said what am I
supposed to do to the restaurant just
walk in with him arm and arm you know
then all your friends you'll be late
right they'll be watching the door you
know and this guy comes in with you arm
in arm who's the
guy it must be her
cousin why do you say that she hasn't
had a boyfriend in three years much less
a good-looking one you know and then
walk in like he's your cousin or
something then just in front of the
table give him a really good kiss you
know like I'm talking gooey okay and
then uh what will they
say not the
cousin not her cousin or a weird cousin
no not her cousin it's not her cousin
and then uh sit down with them and there
will be small talk and menu looking for
10 minutes then what will happen he has
to go to the
bathroom he will go to the he'll excuse
himself and go to the bathroom then what
happens you know
where'd you get it what's the
website you know what club did you go to
where did you mean him then you got to
say n nury
home he looks so
young you got to be like no nursing home
swear to God you know then you have to
tell them about seeds Okay at that point
before he gets back so it's got to be a
little quick and tell him about seeds
tell him I went to nursing planted him
purposely it wasn't an accident it
wasn't
random act act I planted him and I
reaped him Jesus said something like
that right no seriously it's what Jesus
meant plant what you want and then so
and and I planted him quite purposely
and I got him and and he came and I'm
keeping him
by we go to the nursing home together
when can he you and him
stop never you have to keep going
suppose the old person pass away find a
new
one okay and then you will never that
relationship will continue forever be
every year more beautiful it's it's cool
it's fantastic okay
now what will happen to the ladies at
the
table most of them will think you're
crazy I go through this
myself a few of them will try what you
said and it never fails it cannot fail
it's one of the laws of karma it cannot
fail if you go to the nursing home and
you take care of a lonely person and you
take care of your blockers
right uh you must a partner must be
creating from you okay must come no
choice it will come then what will
happen to those lady friends of
yours what should they
do three glasses of
water yeah they should do the same thing
okay what will happen in
time long lines at the nursing homes you
know is she available no she's
booked when can I get in it'll be like a
plumber you know or your
be like your dentist we have an opening
on April 5th
2014 you know and then uh she's got half
an hour you know and that'll be long
lines probably boys and girls will meet
each other in those lines I think but
but try to imagine a world you know I
taught this in Norway we're going back
in a week or something I taught it in
Oslo you know what has happened in Oslo
now the government has announced a
campaign that anyone who brings a person
over 65 to a theater they both get in
freak okay and that has come from that
seene you know and they had a video it's
very beautiful that a whole bunch of
teenagers go to the nursing home and
they they help the old people dress up
and then they take them to the movies
together and the teenagers get in for
free you know so they're all like
uh what would happen in the world if
every single person truly believed that
the only way to become financially
independent were to find a poor person
and to help them what would happen to
Poverty no more
poverty poor people would
become precious there'd be dealers do
you have an
address do you have a four person SP
yeah and I'm not kidding okay imagine a
change trying to imagine a shift in
Civilization itself to a higher
Evolution where everyone believes the
only way to get what they want is to
supply it to someone else first try to
imagine a whole world which is working
that way and that's the evolution of our
world it will come it will come because
it's it works so try to imagine that
okay and that's why I'm here that's what
I want I want
to I'll be very Frank okay I go to China
a
lot Taiwan China single I don't know if
it's some kind
of thing that was in the culture and
never left or something but they get it
quickly and I keep going I keep I'm
invited to 14 more cities in China I
don't have time to go there are 14
cities waiting okay I don't have time to
go a thousand or 2,000 people will come
each time
then I'm being very honest it doesn't
happen in America you know I I give a
talk in America 50 people come 100
people come and they they they have
trouble with the idea they have trouble
I don't know how to express
it somehow their minds are far away from
that idea that you could plant to a
partner or that everyone would be
wealthy everyone would have enough
uh I gave a talk to 1,400 architects in
Florida and uh they said what about oil
and I said according to these principles
how could America assure its oil
supply you tell me they they told me
they got
it give oil make sure China has enough
oil make it your business to assure that
China has enough oil for their progress
make it your the business of your
country and design your
legislation to assure oil supplies to
your
competitors and then new sources of
energy will be invented like the boy in
the nursing home okay it's very cool
system and they 1400 Architects got it
you know and they were all like they all
like from the F and they all like never
work
man and uh just I'm just trying to plan
something these two days okay I just try
to plan something in my home because
it's sad to me my home is the is falling
my country is if you go to China or you
go to other countries this country is
falling it is falling in many ways
financially morally
creatively in many ways this country is
is doomed for failure if it continues on
this course this country will be a third
world country In Our
Lifetime and your kids will be working
in sweat shops for other Count's people
and not the other way around it's coming
it's almost there and and we go live in
China for 6 months and you will see okay
we are behind and we are dropping
quickly and there's a way to make both
countries successful there's a way
to revive our country that would also
make China successful we can both be
successful at the same time you know and
it must come that way it cannot come
through this competition thing you know
we should help other countries be
successful and the seed will make us
successful and until we do that our
country will fail and your kids mark my
words your kids will work in in spread
shops for other countries okay it will
come if we don't do something okay we
must help other countries be successful
give them oil supplies help them develop
their economies even if they get better
than us we should be happy that was what
number eight yeah look how successful
China is man that's cool I'm happy for
your country we should be like that this
other thing that the Press invents about
evil countries and don't believe that
stuff okay everyone's like us and we
must serve them and make them successful
okay and I just think we should try to
spread these ideas in in our country
because if we don't in my opinion we
won't we will go down okay so I leave
you were done I think it would be uh
these ideas could Revive Our Country you
know and and then serve other countries
by serving other countries our country
would would come back and I don't see
any other way okay all right thank you
good
[Music]
night